A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Director of Administrative Services, Roger C. Elliot, Subject Files, Series 3 FA214
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Subject Files, 1904-1974; 1956-1974; 3; 10.2 Cubic Feet 20 boxes
  - V (Miscellaneous) (Box 14)
    - Vakown, Anton 1933-1934 (employee)
    - Vanderbilt, Sanderson 1935 Herald Trib. reporter
    - Van Sickle, Albert 1940 physician sending blood sample
    - Vogelaar, J.P.M. 1929 application to work with Dr. Carrel
    - Von Wendt, Georg 1921 application for appointment
    - Vorobyev (Vorobiev), Vladimir, 1959 USSH scientist offered Research associate position
      See A.E. Mirsky correspondence.
  - Vaccination, 1942 1957 (Box 14)
    Legal opinion on vaccination of employees and release forms Plans for influenza vaccinations.
  - Van Cleve, James 1934-1942 former employee in lab of Dr. Rous and Dr. MacMaster (Box 14)
  - Vending machines, 1947-1961 (Box 14)
  - Veterans Administration (Box 14)
    - Deals primarily with subsistence payments to veterans under educational provisions, 1946-1949
    - Primarily form letters and pamphlets on rules and regulations regarding educational benefits, 1950-1955
      Includes correspondence and forms from New York State Education Dept on RI eligibility as an educational institution.
  - Vibration 1932 report of investigation and measurement of vibrations in Power House (Box 14)
    Includes seismograph readings.
  - Visitors, 2 folders (Box 14)
    Correspondence and announcements dealing with visitors to the Institute for periods of work in the laboratories or scientists coming for lectures and also other visitors.
    - 1927-1949
    - 1950-1962
  - Vitamins, 1921-1924 (Box 14)
    Consists of matters brought up for discussion in coming to a decision on undertaking nutritional studies. Communication between Flexner and Holt. Includes budget figures.
  - W (Miscellaneous)
    - Wadsworth, Augustus B. 1930-1939 NY State Dept of Health (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Ward, Henry B. 1916, Journal of Parasitology
    - Warren Steam Pipe (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Warwick, David Branch. Residue of estate, 1940-1946 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Washburn, F.L. University of Minn, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Washburn, Geo. Request for Cholera vaccine, 1920 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Watson Mfg. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Weaver, Floyd C., 1930 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Webb, Anne 1956 inquiry on her affiliation with WW I unit at RIMR (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Weber, Paul J. 1920-1921 photographer of Princeton laboratories (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Webster Apartments (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Webster, T.P., 1935 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Weeder, Mary A. on sleeping sickness, 1919 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Wegeforth, Harry M. Zoological Society of San Diego, 1925 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Welch, W.M. Mfg., 1932 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Wells Architectural Iron Co. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Wessel Duval & Co. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Westerberg & Williams, 1913 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Westinghouse Electric and Mfg., 1917 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Wheeler, B.I. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Wheeler, C.H. Mfg. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Wheeler Condenser (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Whidden, R.W. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Whipple, George. University of Rochester, 1924 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - White, Alfred T. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - White Enamel Refrigeration (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - White, H.C. Co. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - White Weld & Co. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - White, Wm. Wallace (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Whitenead & Hoag. Employee badges, 1926-1927 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Whitney (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Wiegan, E.L. Co. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Wiese, Randolph A. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Willey, Day Allen (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Williams, Nelson (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Williamson, B.B. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Willmer, W.H. bibliography, 1924 December (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Wilson, H.P. & H.F. Co. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Wilson Welding (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Winckler, G.A. cabinet maker, 1917 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Wissmiller, George Employed as carpenter, 1927-1932 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Wisotsky, Charles 1933-1934 student request for chemicals Witney, Newell 1921-1926 former employee, 1921-1934 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Wolff, Milliam F. sample lighting fixture, 1912 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Wood, Casey A. gift of Ceylanese Ola: palm leaf 'mss of sinholese medicine, 1928 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Wood, Francis C.M.D. Columbia University on Carrel transplants, 1913 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Wood, Leonard. On dysentery vaccine, 1916 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Woodruff, F.H. & Sons. lawn seed, 1932-1944 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Woods, Arthur introduction of Teresa Masterson (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Woodstock Typewriter Co. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Woodward, Geo. on sister's illness (Hodgkins disease) (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Works Progress Administration. area survey request, 1937 1938 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Wright & Hanlon (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Wuest, Nicholas (illness, death and payments to widow, 1933-1942 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Wulffleff, Elsie. Recommendation for past employee, 1913 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Wyeth, John & Brother, 1913 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Wadley & Smythe, 1916-1955 (Box 15)
    Correspondence dealing with plans and plantings on Institute grounds and also orders for floral pieces sent from Institute or Institute personnel on various funerals.
  - War (Box 15)
    - Contracts for research (1942-1943 summary sheet)
    - Production Board, 1942-1943
    - Trade Board, 1918
  - Warburg, Otto, 1924-1949 (Box 15)
    Primarily nine items dealing with Institute support of cancer research.
  - Western Union Telegraph, 1913-1959 (Box 15)
  - White, William A. & Sons, 1917-1942 (Box 15)
    Correspondence relating to management of properties purchased by Institute, but not yet developed for Institute use. This includes area at 67th-68th Sts. and 63rd-64th Sts. Also includes offer to sell property of Flower Hospital to RIMR.
  - Wiesner, B.P., 1940-1942 (Box 15)
    On arrangements to ship rabbits with Brown-Pearce tumor graft to London.
  - Williamsburg restoration (Box 15)
    Includes issue of National Geographic Magazine
  - Woodlawn Cemetery Pamphlets and map (Box 16)
  - Working hours; wages, 1946-1954 (Box 16)
  - Workers, volunteer, 1927-1962 (Box 16)
  - Workman's compensation (see also Employee), 2 folders (Box 16)
    Includes legislation and other materials affecting RIMR Period of self insurance; Insurance Committee recommendations.
    - 1913-1927
    - 1928-1934
  - World Fair in New York City (Box 16)
    - Includes signed typescripts from Grover Whalen and Mayor La Guardia, 1937-1940
  - X-Ray, 3 folders (Box 16)
    - 1913-1930
      Consists of early construction plans; equipment; personnel (Marion Hotopp and Christine McDonald); safety precautions.
    - Primarily new equipment, 1931-1936
    - New equipment, 1937-1956
  - Yale and Towne Mfg. Installation of locks, 1915-1950 (Box 17)
  - Yale University (with registrar) (Box 17)
  - Yellow Taxi (Box 17)
  - Young, John discharged employee, 1936 (Box 17)
  - Young, Saul employee who manufactured pH meter (Box 17)
  - Z (various) (Box 17)
    - Zeisler, Milton
    - Zicherman, J. & Son
    - Zieman, H.
    - Zimmerman, Walter
    - Zinsser, Hans, 1915
      1915 letter regarding possible information from abroad.
    - Zoological Gardens
  - Zoning, 1928-1959 (Box 17)
    Primarily correspondence and materials supplied by George C. Wheeler, engineer and surveyor in relation to hearings on going changes in East Side 1950's and 1960's.
  - Construction, 1904-1955; 1.5 Cubic Feet 3 boxes; 3 Boxes (Boxes 18-20).
    In May 1978 an additional 15 inches (3 boxes) of records dealing with construction were found. Included are records that had been passed along from Edric Smith, Waldo Flinn and finally to Roger C. Elliot. When the Office of Administrative Services was phased out these records were sent to the Archives Office.
    This group of records deals primarily with construction of new facilities or additions and remodeling to existing buildings.
    Arranged roughly in chronological order.
    - Buerkel and Co. Construction Engineers
      - Correspondence between O.S. Staples and E.B. Smith, 1904-1925 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - On heating and ventilation work done in the Animal House, Power House and cooling systems, 1927-1936 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Matthews Construction Co., 1915-1917 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      Work done at the Princeton Department of animal pathology.
    - Western Electric, 1916-1920 (Box 18, Folder 4)
      Regarding supply of incandescent bulbs from Hixon-Electric about a Western-Electric (32A) public address system.
    - Isolation building, 1924-1926 1948-1949 August (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Isolation Building, 1949 October-1956 (Box 18, Folder 6)
      The first work done was the addition of two floors, addition of a sun porch; between 1949-1950 the building was remodeled for a nurses residence. The file includes specifications, correspondence with architects Coolidge, Shepley, Bulfinch and Abbott and various contractors.
    - Fred Brutschy Company 1933-1951 Plumbing, 1929-1951 (Box 18, Folder 7)
      Includes 1929 June-March 1933 records of John MacMillan Company. Relates to work done in the high laboratory and in Princeton (includes copies of New Jersey labor agreements.
    - Alvord and Swift. Steamfitters and cooling systems, 1933-1952 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Summaries and estimates in two groups (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Related to construction of Assembly/Dining room; library; tunnels; Princeton improvements; Power House improvements and grounds development, 1927 May-1929 June
        Includes a pencil sketch by Mr. Coolidge (May 20, 1921) of suggested wood paneling for Assembly/Dining Hall.
      - Correspondence, minutes, summary on Hospital Addition, 1948 November-1953 February
    - Coolidge Shepley Bulfinch & Abbott, 1928-1959 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      Consists of correspondence, estimates, drawings on various construction projects from the work on the Assembly/Dining room; vibration in the power house; construction of permanent fence on 68th St; York Ave and frontage from 67th-68th; development of tennis courts; ventilation in the library building; work on fuel conveyor tunnel; greenhouses and low laboratory building roof; plant pathology in NYC and hospital addition.
    - Construction accounts, 1930 June-1933 June (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - T86; T100; T139 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Library, Assembly-Dining Hall, Pipe tunnel, animal House and connecting unit across 67th Street, generator in Power House and Power Plant additions; new high laboratory; low unit for combined animal and laboratory purposes; service entrance and connecting tunnel; laboratory and animal building at Princeton; greenhouses and tunnel at Princeton, 1930/1931; 1931/1932; 1932/1933; 3 folders (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Hospital addition, 1948-1950 September 19 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Hospital addition, 1950 September 26-1951 May 8 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Hospital addition, 1951 May 15-1952 June 3 (Box 19, Folder 7)
      Consists of minutes of meeting held almost every week dealing with the remodeling of the old building and the building of the addition. At meetings were representatives of RI administration; Coolidge Shepley Bulfinch & Abbott; Fred Butschy Co.; Imperial Sheet Metal Works; Alvord & Swift; Albin Gustafson; Vermilya-Brown Co.
    - Hospital addition specifications, 1949 March-1949 September (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Hospital addition specifications, 1949 October-1950 October (Box 20, Folder 2)
      Consists of building specifications and correspondence for the individual construction stages.
    - Hospital plumbing specifications, 49 pp. and addenda 1-6 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      Fred Butschy, consulting engineer. Includes budget and some correspondence.
    - Hospital electrical wiring, alarm systems, elevators (Box 20, Folder 4)
      Specifications for wiring 32 pp; for coded fire alarm signaling system 5 pp; for alterations in Power House and Engine Room 2 pp.; for elevator equipment 25 pp and 1, 2, 3, addenda.
      Companies are: Albin Gustafson, Kaiser, Muller and Davies and Acme Fire Alarm Co.
    - Hospital heating, ventilation, air-conditioning and refrigeration, 1949 February-1951 March (Box 20, Folder 5)
      Specifications 66 pages and correspondence Handled by Vermilya-Brown and Office of Hollis-French.
    - Hospital Food Service equipment, 1949 June-1951 April (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Refrigeration Plant and Cooling Tower, 1949-1952 (Box 20, Folder 7)
      Under Vermilya-Brown and including Alvard & Swift, Coolidge Shepley Bulfinch & Abbott; Frank Merrill of Office of Hollis-French; York Construction. Correspondence about need to change system so as to recirculate water used.
    - Power Plant addition, 1952-1955 (Box 20, Folder 8)
      Correspondence dealing with estimates, comparisons of different kinds of boilers and steam generating equipment and methods. Plans held in abeyance in 1953 until patterns of growth under new president are defined. Correspondence is with Coolidge Shepley Bulfinch & Abbott, and Merrill Associates.
  - Film: William H. Welch "Reminiscences of the Early Days Of the Medical School" (Johns Hopkins) a sound talk, 1932 June 10; 1 package of two reels, 35 mm composite.
    RAC is unable to provide access to this item. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
    In 1963 a reversal print of the 1932 film was produced by Films of Commerce, Inc.
    The quality of both the film and the sound is poor.
    See Box 10 for a transcript of the Address as well as correspondence with W.G. MacCallum and Alan M. Chesney regarding copies of the film and the ownership of the film.
    Date is date recorded.
    Seperated to the RAC Film Vault, May 1983.